John Alden Mason Papers 1904-1967 Mss.B.M384
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1926-1967; 20 linear feet
  - Maffe, Richard J (Box 24)
  - Magnino, Carlo (Box 24)
  - Magrath, Willis H (Box 24)
  - Mahon, Robert P Jr (Box 24)
  - Malagon, Javier (Box 24)
    - Satterthwaite, Linton, Jr (Box 24)
  - Maldonado, Juan J (Box 24)
  - Malinowski, Bronislow (Box 24)
  - Mallery, Chester D (Box 24)
  - Mandel, Estelle (Box 24)
    - Nixon, Henrietta (Box 24)
  - Mandel, Herbert (Box 24)
  - Mandiola, Samuel (Box 24)
  - Manning, Margaret E (Box 24)
  - Manoukian, Mrs. Helen (Box 24)
  - Manufacturers & Bankers Club of Philadelphia (Box 24)
    - Lloyd, W J M (Box 24)
  - María Torroja, José (Box 24)
  - Marceau, Henri (Box 24)
  - March, Douglas D H (Box 24)
  - Marchant, Alexander (Box 24)
  - Margáin, Hugo B (Box 24)
  - Margain, Carlos R (Box 24)
  - Mariá, Hildeberto (Box 24)
  - Marin, Juan (Box 24)
  - Mariscal, Mario (Box 24)
  - Markert, Mr (Box 24)
  - Markert, W. A (Box 24)
  - Marques, A N Co (Box 24)
  - Marquina, Ignacio (Box 24)
  - Marsh, Elizabeth (Box 24)
  - Marsh, Roy S (Box 24)
  - Marshall, Byron C (Box 24)
  - Marshall, Donald S (Box 24)
    - Stimson, J. Frank (Box 24)
  - Marshall, Nettie W (Box 24)
  - Martínez, J. D (Box 24)
  - Marti, Samuel (Box 24)
  - Martin, G. F (Box 24)
  - Martin, George Castor (Box 24)
  - Martin, Harry L (Box 24)
  - Martin, Paul S (Box 24)
  - Martin, Richard A A (Box 24)
    - Martin, Patty (Box 24)
  - Martin, Sydney E (Box 24)
  - Martin, Volley R (Box 24)
  - Martinez C., Pedro (Box 24)
  - Martinez Cantón, Eduardo (Box 24)
  - Martinez del Rio, Pablo (Box 24)
    - Spier, Leslie (Box 24)
  - Martinez del Rio, Pedro (Box 24)
  - Martinez Hernandez, Juan (Box 24)
  - Martinez, Elba Aurora (Box 24)
    - Wauchope, Robert (Box 24)
  - Marye, William B (Box 24)
  - Maryland Historical Society (Box 24)
  - Mason, Gregory (Box 25)
  - Mason, Henry S (Box 25)
  - Mason, John Alden. Bibliography (Box 25)
  - Mason, Leonard (Box 25)
  - Mason, Ronald J (Box 25)
  - Mason, Sidney (Box 25)
  - Master Reporting Co.,Inc (Box 25)
    - Sweeney, F. S (Box 25)
  - Masud, M (Box 25)
    - Brown, Norman W (Box 25)
  - Matheson, W. J (Box 25)
  - Mathiessen, Therkel (Box 25)
  - Mathiot, Madeleine (Box 25)
  - Mathis, Emma M (Box 25)
  - Matisse, Pierre (Box 25)
  - Matney, James J (Box 25)
  - Matson, Daniel Shaw (Box 25)
  - Matson, Frederick R (Box 25)
  - Matthew, Mrs. Anna (Box 25)
  - Matthews, E. O (Box 25)
  - Matthews, G Herbert (Box 25)
  - Matthews, Marilyn (Box 25)
  - Maverick, Lucy (Box 25)
  - Mayer, Charles G (Box 25)
  - Mayer-Oakes, William J (Box 25)
  - Mayflower Publishing Co.,Inc (Box 25)
    - Patterson, Xi B (Box 25)
  - Mayhew, Benjamin A (Box 25)
  - Mead, Charles W (Box 25)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 25)
  - Means, J H (Box 25)
  - Means, Philip Ainsworth (Box 25)
  - Mears, Bryant F (Box 25)
  - Mears, Mrs. Leverett B (Box 25)
  - Mechling, William H (Box 25)
  - Meggers, Betty J (Box 25)
  - Meggers, Betty Jane (Box 25)
  - Meier, E Max (Box 25)
  - Meigs, Ruth Averell (Box 25)
  - Mejia Xesspe, Toribio (Box 25)
  - Melvin, Frank W (Box 25)
  - Memoranda on the University Museum matters (Box 25)
  - Mendenhall, John C (Box 25)
    - Mason, John E (Box 25)
  - Mendez Pereira, Octavio (Box 25)
  - Mendez, Antonio (Box 25)
  - Mendizabel, Miguel O de (Box 25)
  - Mendoza F, Santiago (Box 25)
  - Mengel, Levi W (Box 25)
  - Mengin, Ernst (Box 25)
  - Menzel, Brigette (Box 25)
  - Menzel, Dorothy (Box 25)
  - Mercer, Henry C (Box 25)
  - Mercher, Allen J (Box 25)
  - Merrill, Edwin (Box 25)
  - Merrill, Robert H (Box 25)
    - Timmer, H (Box 25)
  - Merrill, Robert T (Box 25)
  - Merritt, A (Box 25)
  - Mesoamerican Handbook (Box 25)
  - Messenger, Ernest A (Box 25)
  - Métraux, A (Box 25)
    - Oddon, Yvonne (Box 25)
    - Wardle, Harriet Newell (Box 25)
  - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Box 25)
    - Kay, Janet (Box 25)
    - Minnelli, Vincente (Box 25)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 25)
  - Mexican gold objects - Insurance value of stolen.. (Box 25)
  - Mexican Valley project (Box 25)
  - Mexico Instituto Nacional de Antropologia e Historia (Box 25)
  - Mexico, Departamento de Monumentos (Box 25)
    - Marquina, Ignacio (Box 25)
    - Tore, Alfonso (Box 25)
  - Mexico. Banco Nacional de (Box 25)
  - Mexico. Secretaria de Educacion Publica (Box 25)
    - Valle, Rafael Heliodoro (Box 25)
  - Mexico. Tour of archaeological sites (Box 25)
  - Meyer, Howard A (Box 26)
  - Michael, Henry (Box 26)
  - Michelson, Truman (Box 26)
  - Mickey, Barbara (Box 26)
  - Mickey, John and Barbara, 1955; 1 items (Box 26)
    Re: Southern Tepehuan.
  - Middleton, Dorothy. Introduction to the book of.. (Box 26)
  - Midlay, Mrs. Ralph (Box 26)
  - Mier y Teran, Jose (Box 26)
  - Miles, Elton (Box 26)
  - Miller, Catharine (Box 26)
  - Miller, George W (Box 26)
  - Miller, Mariane B (Box 26)
  - Miller, Max (Box 26)
  - Miller, Olive Beaupré (Box 26)
  - Miller, Towne L (Box 26)
  - Miller, W. O (Box 26)
  - Miller, Walter S (Box 26)
  - Miller, William C (Box 26)
  - Milligan, Jean E (Box 26)
  - Milliken, William M (Box 26)
  - Millis, Charlotte (Box 26)
  - Mills, George (Box 26)
  - Milton (Box 26)
  - Mimenza Castillo, Ricardo (Box 26)
  - Mindszenthy, Bart A (Box 26)
  - Minnesota Historical Society (Box 26)
  - Miscellany (Box 26)
  - Mitchell, Claude R (Box 26)
  - Mitchell, Hazel C (Box 26)
  - Moberg, Gosta (Box 26)
  - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 26)
  - Moffet, Blair A (Box 26)
  - Mohr, Charles E (Box 26)
  - Monday, H A (Box 26)
  - Mongin, Alfred (Box 26)
  - Monigle, Joseph (Box 26)
  - Monroe, Katherine M (Box 26)
  - Monshower, Harold (Box 26)
  - Monski, John (Box 26)
  - Montabone, Alphonse (Box 26)
  - Montclair, N.J., Art Museum (Box 26)
  - Montgomery, George R (Box 26)
  - Montgomery, J. A (Box 26)
  - Montgomery, Knox Hall (Box 26)
  - Mook, Maurice A (Box 26)
  - Moore, Clyde F (Box 26)
  - Moore, Helen (Box 26)
  - Moore, Leslie (Box 26)
  - Moore, Mrs. William H (Box 26)
  - Moorehead, Warren King (Box 26)
    - Dorrance, Miss (Box 26)
  - Moose, Mrs. Helen A (Box 26)
  - Morales Cabrera, Pablo (Box 26)
  - Mordel, Albert (Box 26)
  - Morefield, S V (Box 26)
  - Morey, Charles R (Box 26)
  - Morey,Florence (Box 26)
  - Morgadanes, Dolores (Box 26)
  - Morgadanes, Roberto (Box 26)
  - Morgan, K. P (Box 26)
  - Morgan, R. G (Box 26)
  - Morgan, Raymond (Box 26)
  - Morice, A. C (Box 26)
  - Morley, Charles Lucien (Box 26)
  - Morley, Sylvanus G (Box 26)
    - Long, Boaz (Box 26)
  - Morris, Earl H (Box 26)
  - Morris, Katherine (Box 26)
  - Morris, L A (Box 26)
  - Morris, Lawrence S (Box 26)
  - Morris, Lucy M (Box 26)
  - Morrs, Noel (Box 26)
  - Mostny, Greta (Box 26)
  - Mothers Assistance Fund (Box 26)
    - Cavin, Evalyn T (Box 26)
  - Moura Pessoa, Maria Alice (Box 26)
  - Mousley, W Ashton (Box 26)
  - Moyer, F. E (Box 26)
  - Mueller, Harold (Box 26)
  - Muir, John M (Box 26)
  - Munn, Henry T (Box 26)
  - Murdock, George P (Box 26)
  - Murray, Elsie (Box 26)
  - Murray, Jessie Welles (Box 26)
  - Murray, Louise Welles (Box 26)
  - Murray, R. Stuart (Box 26)
  - Muses, Charles A (Box 26)
  - Museum materials (Box 26)
  - Museum Nacional de Arqueologia (Box 26)
  - Musser, Paul H (Box 26)
  - Mutzinger, John G (Box 26)
  - Myers, Charles F (Box 26)
  - Myers, George Hewitt (Box 26)
  - Nájera, J H (Box 26)
  - Nachtingall, William E (Box 26)
  - Nagel, Charles (Box 26)
  - Nagel, Christine (Box 26)
  - Nalle, Albert (Box 26)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 26)
    - Morgan, Thomas Henry (Box 26)
  - National Education Assoc. of the U. S (Box 26)
    - Prior, F Erle (Box 26)
  - National Frontiersmen's Assoc (Box 26)
    - Airey, J. W. E (Box 26)
  - National Geographic Magazine (Box 26)
    - Fisher, Franklin (Box 26)
  - National Geographic Society (Box 26)
    - Borah, Leo A (Box 26)
    - Fisher, Franklin (Box 26)
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert (Box 26)
    - Hildebrand, J R (Box 26)
    - Vosburgh, Frederick G (Box 26)
  - National Research Council: Div. of Anthropology and Psychology (Box 27)
    - Bentley, Madison (Box 27)
    - Britten, Marion Hale (Box 27)
    - Guthe, Carl E (Box 27)
  - National Research Council (Box 27)
  - National Research Council (Box 27)
    - Barnum, Susie C (Box 27)
    - Britten, Marion Hale (Box 27)
    - Cole, Fay-Cooper (Box 27)
    - Cooper, John M (Box 27)
    - Dunlap, Knight (Box 27)
    - Guthe, Carl E (Box 27)
    - Hunter, W S (Box 27)
    - Poffenberger, T R (Box 27)
    - Sapir, Edward (Box 27)
  - National Roster of Scientific & Specialized Personnel (Box 27)
  - Natschke, E. E (Box 27)
  - Natural History (Box 27)
    - American Museum of Natural History (Box 27)
    - Goddard, P. E (Box 27)
    - Hawthorne, Daniel (Box 27)
    - Nelson, N. C (Box 27)
    - Tschopik, Harry, Jr (Box 27)
    - Weitzner, Bella (Box 27)
    - Weyer, Edward M., Jr (Box 27)
    - Wissler, Clark (Box 27)
  - Nauss, Ralph W (Box 27)
    - Wardle, Harriet Newell (Box 27)
  - Navarro, Tomás, Tomás (Box 27)
  - Nehlig, J P (Box 27)
  - Neidengard, Carl D (Box 27)
  - Nelson, Dorothy M (Box 27)
  - Nelson, Eugene W (Box 27)
  - Nelson, Harry R (Box 27)
  - Nelson, Mrs. Helen (Box 27)
  - Nelson, N. C (Box 27)
    - Bird, Junius (Box 27)
  - Nelson, Nels Christian, obituary (Box 27)
  - Nerr, Allen (Box 27)
  - Neumann, Georg K (Box 27)
  - Neville Public Museum (Box 27)
    - Mason, Ronald J (Box 27)
    - Quinn, James L (Box 27)
  - New installations of 3 American Halls -, June 1951 (Box 27)
  - New Jersey, Dept. of Conservation & Development (Box 27)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 27)
    - Miner, Eunice Thomas (Box 27)
    - Miner, Roy Waldo (Box 27)
    - Schlaikjer, Erich M (Box 27)
    - Waterman, Richard A (Box 27)
    - Yoell, Florence Moore (Box 27)
  - New York Public Library (Box 27)
  - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railway Co (Box 27)
  - New Yorker (Box 27)
    - Wallace, Kevin (Box 27)
  - Newberry Library (Box 27)
    - Butler, Ruth Lapham (Box 27)
    - McKinley, Dorothy (Box 27)
  - Newcomb, Russell (Box 27)
  - Newell, Joyce (Box 27)
  - Newell, William B (Box 27)
  - Newlands, Thomas (Box 27)
  - Newman, Franklin B (Box 27)
  - Newman, Marshall T (Box 27)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 27)
  - Newton, Mrs. A. Edward (Box 27)
  - Newton, Earle W (Box 27)
    - Pennsylvania Museum & Historical Comm (Box 27)
  - Newton, John J (Box 27)
  - Nichols, Roy Franklin (Box 27)
  - Nida, Eugene A (Box 27)
  - Niehaus, Hazel (Box 27)
  - Niemeyer (Box 27)
  - Nieto, Luis (Box 27)
  - Nippgen, Joseph (Box 27)
  - Nitzsche, George E (Box 27)
    - Speck, Frank G (Box 27)
  - Niven, William (Box 27)
  - Noble, Kingsley (Box 27)
  - Noguera, Eduardo (Box 27)
  - Noonan, Julia A (Box 27)
  - Nordenskiöld, Erland (Box 27)
  - Nordquist, Del (Box 27)
  - Norona, Delf (Box 27)
    - Milton, Charles J (Box 27)
  - Nort, Richard Leighton van (Box 27)
  - North American Ethnology Exhibit, 1933 (Box 27)
  - Northern Arizona Society of Science and Art (Box 27)
  - Northern Cheyenne Tribe (Box 27)
    - Littlebird, Harry (Box 27)
  - Northwest Coast Indian materials in the Museum (Box 27)
  - Norton, Mary Lou (Box 27)
  - Notes on Middle American Arcaheology and Ethnology, 1944 (Box 27)
  - Nuddle, Seymour Arthur (Box 27)
  - Numismatic & Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia (Box 27)
    - Davis, Joseph A (Box 27)
  - Nusbaum, Jesse L (Box 27)
  - Nusbaum, M. G (Box 27)
  - Nuttall, Zelia (Box 27)
  - Oakley, Kenneth P (Box 27)
  - Oakley, Louise G (Box 27)
  - Ober, J. Hambleton (Box 27)
  - Oberly, Henry Sherman (Box 27)
  - O'Bryan, Deric (Box 27)
  - Observations on the function of the museum in anthropology (Box 27)
  - Oestereicher, Mrs. Elda M (Box 27)
  - Oetteking (Box 27)
  - Oetteking, Bruno (Box 27)
  - Ogden, Warren C (Box 27)
  - O'Halloran, John (Box 27)
  - Olafson, Sigfus (Box 27)
  - Olano, G (Box 27)
  - Olbrechts, Frans M (Box 27)
  - Oldock (?), Frederick M (Box 27)
  - Olsen (Box 27)
  - Omwake, H. Geiger (Box 27)
    - Ackerman, Robert (Box 27)
  - [On the Races of Man] (Box 28)
  - Onan, D. W., Sons (Box 28)
  - Ongley, W G (Box 28)
  - Onondaga Radio Broadcasting Corporation (Box 28)
  - Oppenheim, Victor (Box 28)
  - Orchard, William O (Box 28)
  - Oregon Museum of Fine Arts (Box 28)
    - Walton, Pauline (Box 28)
  - Orfila Reynal, Arnoldo (Box 28)
  - Ortega, Tomás (Box 28)
    - Núnez, F F (Box 28)
  - Ortiz, Sergio Elias (Box 28)
  - Osborne, Lilly de Jongh (Box 28)
    - Kelsey, Vera (Box 28)
  - Osborne, Mrs. E. A (Box 28)
  - Osgood, C. B (Box 28)
  - Osgood, Cornelius (Box 28)
  - Osgood, Wilfred H (Box 28)
  - Oster, Ted (Box 28)
  - Ostroff, Isidor (Box 28)
  - Ott, Jack (Box 28)
  - Ott, Orville M (Box 28)
  - Outhwaite, Leonard (Box 28)
  - Owens, Edward J (Box 28)
  - Packard, R M (Box 28)
  - Paddock, John (Box 28)
  - Painted cave petroglyphs in Puerto Rico (Box 28)
  - Painter, Mrs. Toraine W (H Mc M) (Box 28)
  - Pallotta, L Gori (Box 28)
    - Morley, Sylvanus G (Box 28)
    - Satterthwaite, Linton, Jr (Box 28)
    - Tozzer, Alfred (Box 28)
      re: original ms. of the Chilam Balam of Chumayel
  - Palmatary, Anna Laura (Box 28)
  - Palmatary, Helen C (Box 28)
  - Palmer House (Box 28)
  - Palmer, Arthur (Box 28)
  - Palmer, M. Helen (Box 28)
    - Newman, Marshall T (Box 28)
    - Smithsonian Institution (Box 28)
  - Palmer, Mrs. E Carleton (Box 28)
  - Palomo, Francisco (Box 28)
  - Pan American Institute of Geography & History (Box 28)
    - Caso, Alfonso (Box 28)
  - Pan American Union (Box 28)
    - Brown, Elsie (Box 28)
    - Debenedetti, Salvador (Box 28)
    - Gusinde, Martin (Box 28)
    - James, Concha Romero (Box 28)
    - Lehmann-Nitsche, R (Box 28)
    - Macdermott, Isabel K (Box 28)
    - Posnansky, Arthur (Box 28)
    - Rivas, Raimundo (Box 28)
    - Salas, Julio C (Box 28)
    - Silva, A C Simoens da (Box 28)
    - Snodgrass, H C (Box 28)
    - Tavera-Acosta, B (Box 28)
  - Panamerican Association of Phila (Box 28)
    - Griffin, Norman J (Box 28)
    - Morrisey, Francis J Jr (Box 28)
    - Palmer, Thomas W (Box 28)
  - Pan-American Union (Box 28)
  - Panamericanismo., 1942-46, 1951 (Box 28)
    - Adams, Hugh T (Box 28)
    - Alexander, John W (Box 28)
    - Angney, Kenneth C (Box 28)
    - Auritsky, Eva (Box 28)
    - Baily, R W (Box 28)
    - Boylon, Jessie R (Box 28)
    - Brickell, Herschel (Box 28)
    - Bright, A F (Box 28)
    - Cadwallader, Helen Washburn (Box 28)
    - Carbough, Hazel (Box 28)
    - Castaneda, Chepita de (Box 28)
    - Chaninel, Elizabeth (Box 28)
    - Cleven, N Andrew N (Box 28)
    - Conangla, Raul C (Box 28)
    - Conaugh, Mrs R (Box 28)
    - Cooper-Greene Co (Box 28)
    - Correale, Carmela M (Box 28)
    - Correale, Virginia C (Box 28)
    - Cotto-Thorner, Alfredo (Box 28)
    - Darlington, Mr & Mrs Charles (Box 28)
    - Davies, Richard L (Box 28)
    - Davis, Malcolm W (Box 28)
    - Dodd, Mead & Co (Box 28)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Co (Box 28)
    - Dougherty, Edward C (Box 28)
    - Duell Sloan & Pearce (Box 28)
    - Espinosa, Richard O (Box 28)
    - Farrar & Rinehart (Box 28)
    - Finch, George A (Box 28)
    - Gamio, Manuel (Box 28)
    - Gonzalez, Olga (Box 28)
    - Gordon, Harmon Y (Box 28)
    - Gorman, William L (Box 28)
    - Gutierrez, Jaquin (Box 28)
    - Griffith, Norman J (Box 28)
    - Hall, Gertrude (Box 28)
    - Haines, C Robert (Box 28)
    - Harcourt, Brace & Co (Box 28)
    - Harnoncourt, Rene d' (Box 28)
    - Harper & Brothers (Box 28)
    - Hastings House (Box 28)
    - Hellmer, Joseph R (Box 28)
    - Hoyos, Luis G (Box 28)
    - Hutchinson, C A (Box 28)
    - Inter-American Center (Box 28)
    - Ivanissevich, Oscar (Box 28)
    - Jackson, Chevalier L (Box 28)
    - Jones, Katharine (Box 28)
    - Jones, Paul (Box 28)
    - Jordan, Mrs. Harry Thomas (Box 28)
    - Keener, Ruth (Box 28)
    - Knopf, Alfred (Box 28)
    - Krauskopf, Manfred R (Box 28)
    - Langman, Ida K (Box 28)
    - Lefferts, Marie (Box 28)
    - Lippincott, J B & Co (Box 28)
    - MacCarry, Mrs. Noel J (Box 28)
    - MacMillan Co (Box 28)
    - Molina, Ana Maria de (Box 28)
    - Moretzsohn, David B L (Box 28)
    - Morris, Edward S (Box 28)
    - Mullen, Eilen (Box 28)
    - Onofrio B, Maridla d' (Box 28)
    - Ormandy, Eugene (Box 28)
    - Paula, Jose Manuel (Box 28)
    - Powell, Philip M (Box 28)
    - Random House (Box 28)
    - Rauffenbart, Walter E (Box 28)
    - Rehn, James A G (Box 28)
    - Reyes, Alejandro C (Box 28)
    - Robbins, J Stanton (Box 28)
    - Sartori, Frank A, Jr (Box 28)
    - Scribner's, Charles, Sons (Box 28)
    - Shattuck, Virginia C (Box 28)
    - Sesso, Mr (Box 28)
    - Shipley, Morris S (Box 28)
    - Silver, Lillian C (Box 28)
    - Simon & Schuster (Box 28)
    - Sister M Helen Patricia (Box 28)
    - Smith, Richard R (Box 28)
    - Stevenson, John A (Box 28)
    - T, Nona (Box 28)
    - Tober, Mary G (Box 28)
    - Unknown (Box 28)
    - Vaillant, George C (Box 28)
    - Villadeamigo Ellis, Zoila N (Box 28)
    - Welles, Sumner (Box 28)
    - Whitaker, Arthur P (Box 28)
    - Williams, C R (Box 28)
    - Wolff, Katharine (Box 28)
    - Woodruff (?), Eleaner T (Box 28)
    - Woodward, A (Box 28)
    - Ziff-Davis Publishing Co (Box 28)
  - Pancheco Cruz, Santiago (Box 28)
  - Pancoast, Charles A (Box 28)
  - Pando, Oscar (Box 28)
  - Paramount Pictures Inc (Box 28)
    - Percey, Helen Gladys (Box 28)
  - Paris, France. Musée D'Ethnographie (Box 28)
    - Lehmann, Heinz (Box 28)
  - Park, J Theodore (Box 28)
  - Park, Nelson R (Box 28)
  - Park, Willard Z (Box 28)
  - Parker, Arthur C (Box 28)
  - Parker, Laurence B (Box 28)
  - Parker, Mac (Box 28)
  - Parmenter, Ross (Box 28)
    - Nuttall, Zelia to Sara Stevenson (Box 28)
      (6 letters - typed copies)
    - Nuttall, Zelia to President and Borad of Managers of Dept. of Archeology of University of Penna (Box 28)
      (xerox copy)
    - San Francisco Examiner (Box 28)
      (typed copy of article in issue of December 3, 1916)
  - Parra Rojas, Joaquin (Box 28)
  - Parris, Fred P (Box 28)
  - Parsons, Robert (Box 28)
  - Pasadena Art Institute (Box 28)
  - Patterson, Ernest Minor (Box 28)
  - Patterson, J. T (Box 28)
  - Paty, Frank C (Box 28)
  - Paul, William L (Box 28)
  - Paulsen, A. G (Box 28)
  - Pawling, Robert (Box 28)
  - Paxson, A. M (Box 28)
  - Paxson, Henry D (Box 28)
  - Payne, A. W (Box 28)
  - Payne, Alan (Box 28)
  - Paz, Miguel (Box 28)
  - Peabody Museum of Archeology and Ethnology. Harvard University (Box 29)
    - Ashenden, Constance (Box 29)
    - Scott, Donald (Box 29)
  - Peabody Museum, Harvard University (Box 29)
  - Peabody Museum, Yale University (Box 29)
  - Pearce, Charles A (Box 29)
  - Pearce, J. E (Box 29)
  - Pearl, Aaron (Box 29)
  - Pearsall, Leigh M (Box 29)
  - Pector, Désiré (Box 29)
  - Peets, Orville H (Box 29)
  - Pegram, J. C (Box 29)
  - Peirce, F. Lamont (Box 29)
  - Peirce, Thomas May, III (Box 29)
  - Peirson, Walter (Box 29)
  - Pelican Book papers (personal) (Box 29)
  - Pelican Book, correspondence (Box 29)
  - Penguin Books, Ltd (Box 29)
    - Siddall, Patricia (Box 29)
  - Pennell, Francis W (Box 29)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Science (Box 29)
  - Pennsylvania Folklore Society (Box 29)
  - Pennsylvania Securities Commission (Box 29)
  - Pennsylvania State Employment Service (Box 29)
    - McFarland, Joseph, Jr (Box 29)
    - Pedraza, Marian S (Box 29)
  - Pennypacker, James L (Box 29)
  - Pennypacker, Samuel W., III (Box 29)
  - Penrose, Thomas F (Box 29)
  - Pent, Philip H (Box 29)
  - Pepe, Braz Francisco (Box 29)
  - Pepper, William (Box 29)
  - Pereira Salas, Eugenio (Box 29)
  - Pereira, Octavio (Box 29)
  - Perez Sucs., Alvaro F (Box 29)
  - Perfilieff, V (Box 29)
    - Silverman, R (Box 29)
  - Perfilieff, Vladimir (Box 29)
  - Perrill, Helen (Box 29)
  - Personal reprint exchange list (Box 29)
  - Pessoa, Marialice de Moura (Box 29)
  - Pessoa, Mrs. Maria A (Box 29)
  - Petersen, Fritz Herbert (Box 29)
  - Peterson, William A (Box 29)
    - Benham, J. W (Box 29)
  - Petit, Alan (Box 29)
  - Petrullo, Vincenzo J (Box 29)
    - Guggenheim, John Simon, [UNK] (Box 29)
    - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 29)
  - Petrullo, Vincenzo (Box 29)
  - Petta, J. B (Box 29)
  - Pfizenmayer, Edna Warren Mason (Box 29)
  - Phila., First National Bank of (Box 29)
    - Byers, Lowell B (Box 29)
  - Philadelphia Record (Box 29)
    - Murphy, Frank (Box 29)
    - Stern, Juliet Lit (Box 29)
  - Philadelphia Anthropological Society. Hallowell volume (Box 29)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer (Box 29)
    - Missett, Mary (Box 29)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art (Box 29)
    - Wolfe, Jane (Box 29)
  - Philadelphia Transportation Co (Box 29)
  - Philbrook, Francis S (Box 29)
  - Phillips, A. Russell (Box 29)
  - Phillips, Ethel (Box 29)
  - Phillips, George Brinton (Box 29)
  - Pickett, William F (Box 29)
  - Picon, Lillian (Box 29)
  - Picture exhibits, (Catherwood, Honduras and Maya, etc.), 1950 (Box 29)
  - Piedras Negras exhibit (Box 29)
  - Pierce, Ray G (Box 29)
  - Pierce, Walter (Box 29)
  - Pijoan, Jose (Box 29)
  - Pijoan, Joseph (Box 29)
  - Pike, Frederick B (Box 29)
  - Pike, Kenneth L (Box 29)
  - Piling, Norman B (Box 29)
  - Pindeo del Aguila, Victor M (Box 29)
  - Pinedo, Victor M (Box 29)
  - Pipe, Jane (Box 29)
  - Pittman, Dean (Box 29)
  - Pleasants, Frederick R (Box 29)
  - Plowman, Suzanne Crozier (Box 29)
  - PM (Box 29)
    - Leslie, Robert L (Box 29)
  - Poffenberger, A T (Box 29)
  - Pohl, Frederick J (Box 29)
  - Pollak, Adele (Box 30)
  - Pollan, Arthur A (Box 30)
  - Pollock, Harry (Box 30)
  - Polytechnic Institute of Puerto Rico (Box 30)
    - Mosholder, Wilma (Box 30)
  - Pompa y Pompa, Antonio (Box 30)
  - Poole, Earle L (Box 30)
  - Poole, Frederic (Box 30)
  - Poole, Sidman P (Box 30)
  - Popenoe, Wilson (Box 30)
    - The Explorers Club (Box 30)
  - Porras Troconis, G (Box 30)
  - Posnansky, Arturo (Box 30)
  - Post, Edward (Box 30)
  - Potter, Kenneth (Box 30)
  - Pottstown Mercury (Box 30)
    - Dostal, Frank J (Box 30)
  - Powell, Alfred (Box 30)
  - Powell, Allen (Box 30)
  - Powell, Benjamin C (Box 30)
  - Powell, Bernard W (Box 30)
  - Powell, Fr. Peter J (Box 30)
  - Powers, J. Lincoln, Jr (Box 30)
  - Pratt, Robert Y (Box 30)
  - Precision Film Laboratories, Inc (Box 30)
  - PreColumbian American Art (Box 30)
  - Prescott, Kenneth W (Box 30)
  - Preston, Lillie D (Box 30)
  - Preston, M. H (Box 30)
  - Pretz, Mrs. Geneviev Maxwell (Box 30)
  - Preuss, K (Box 30)
  - Preuss, Konrad Theodor (Box 30)
  - Preuss, M (Box 30)
  - Price, Ernest B (Box 30)
  - Price, Weston A (Box 30)
  - Prince, H. M (Box 30)
  - Priseman, E H (Box 30)
  - Proskouriakofr, Tatiana (Box 30)
  - Protopapas, D. N (Box 30)
  - Public Ledger (Box 30)
    - Henderson, Victor (Box 30)
    - Kwapil, Joseph F (Box 30)
  - Puerta Rican Folklore: copied from original taken in quasi-Iloutic (?) script, Ricardo Alegria, 1957 (Box 30)
  - Puetra Rican Folklore (Box 30)
  - Puhr, Arthur (Box 30)
  - Puhr, Wilber J (Box 30)
  - Pullen, Mrs. Harriet (Box 30)
  - Purdom, J Leslie (Box 30)
  - Purdy, Herbert McLean (Box 30)
  - Purnell, Harold W T (Box 30)
    - Hutchinson, Henry H (Box 30)
  - Putnam's, G B, Sons (Box 30)
    - Balch, Earle H (Box 30)
  - Quain, Fannie Dunn (Box 30)
  - Quigley, Francis T (Box 30)
  - Quimby, George (Box 30)
  - Quinn, W. D (Box 30)
  - Röck, Friedrich (Box 30)
  - Röck, Fritz (Box 30)
  - Rachlin, Carol K (Box 30)
  - Radin, Paul (Box 30)
    - Radin, Doris (Box 30)
  - Rainey, Froelich G (Box 30)
  - Ramirez Sendoya, Pedro Jose (Box 30)
  - Ramirez, P. R (Box 30)
  - Ramsay, Helen (Box 30)
  - Random House, Inc (Box 30)
    - Maule, Harry E (Box 30)
  - Rankin, Louis, 1942; 2 items (Box 30)
    Re: Cocama, Cocamilla, Chama (Pano), Campa, and Amuesha languages of Peru.
  - Rasmussen, Alex (Box 30)
  - Raven, Mrs. Ralph W., Jr (Box 30)
  - Rawdon, C. H (Box 30)
  - Ray, Cyrus N (Box 30)